Hi my name is Ashley Ludman from Seaside Yoga here today to talk to you about hot yoga.
So a few years ago Bikram yoga was developed and franchised by Bikram Chadroy.
From that branched out a lot of styles of hot yoga that didn't really have anything to do with the franchise of Bikram yoga.
But in essence hot yoga is a yoga style that is practiced within a room that is deliberately heated.
Sometimes up to temperatures of a hundred and ten degrees.
And the purpose of heating the room in a hot yoga class is to create greater detoxification benefits.
So not only are you internally heating through your breath and through the movement of postures from one posture to the next, but the room is externally heated.
And there should be a little bit of humanity within that, that sphere of the room.
You may find various sequences in a hot yoga class where Bikram yoga is one particular sequence and one particular class of twenty six postures.
In the hot yoga class you may find that you are moving through postures in a more flowing way.
So hot yoga, hot room, hot practice, hope you enjoy it.